人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
■
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
翻译  Silmar
翻译  小熊嘟嘟
翻译 潇湘月影
翻译 树树
翻译 泰斯
校对 Silmar
校对  泰斯·雪诺
时间轴 加森
时间轴 全家幸福筒
时间轴 imok
特效/后期 吉吉·波顿
顾问 屈畅(ccxx)
总监 泰斯·雪诺
改编自《冰与火之歌》
原著 乔治·R·R·马丁
权力的游戏
第四季 第四集
我的名字
My name
是灰虫子
is Grey Worm.
我来自
I come from
盛夏群鸟
the Summer "Ills."
群岛
Isles.
盛夏群岛
Summer Isles.
我来自纳斯岛
I am from an island called Naath.
他们什么时候抓你
When they took you?
我是什么时候被抓的
"When did they take me?"
那年我五岁
I was five years old.
你记得你的家乡吗
You remember your home?
我记得被他们抓上船离开海岸
I remember when they rowed us away from shore.
沙滩那么白
How white the beaches were.
树那么高
How tall the trees.
我记得我的村子燃起大火
And I remember my village burning.
烟直冲到天上
Smoke rising into the sky.
你还记得家乡吗
Do you remember your home?
无垢者
Unsullied.
一直都是无垢者
Always Unsullied.
成为无垢者之前  什么都没有
Before Unsullied, nothing.
不是那样的
That's not true.
或许有一天你会回到盛夏群岛
Perhaps one day you will return to the Summer Isles.
我不想回去
I don't want return.
杀死伟主
Kill the masters.
教学顺利吗
How are the lessons coming?
非常顺利  陛下
Very well, Your Grace.
弥桑黛是好老师  我的女王
Missandei is teacher good, my queen.
你们得改天再学
You'll have to continue later.
时候到了
It's time.
你们听到她说的了
她说她是来解放我们的
你是个傻瓜
伟主们太强大
她会保护我们
她打败了伟主的冠军
她有一支大军
你们想戴着锁链过一辈子吗
我想活下去
你看到他们怎么对那些孩子了
你说他们会怎么对我们
我经历过两次奴隶暴动  小子
永远是同样的结局
伟主掌权  奴隶没命
凡人皆有一死
但我向你们保证
自由活一日  胜过镣铐度一生
你是谁
小人名叫灰虫子
婴儿时就被阿斯塔波的善主带走
养大训练成无垢者
如今我为丹妮莉丝而战
龙之母
解放者
你是无垢者
你还没学会走路  他们就教你如何战斗
我们不是战士
我们没受过训练
没有武器
城里奴隶的人数是伟主的三倍
没人能给予你们自由  我的兄弟
你们若想要自由
就要自己去夺取
杀死伟主
母亲  母亲  母亲
Mhysa! Mhysa! Mhysa!
母亲  母亲  母亲  母亲
Mhysa! Mhysa! Mhysa! Mhysa!
母亲  母亲
Mhysa! Mhysa!
提醒我一下  乔拉爵士
Remind me, Ser Jorah,
伟主们在路标上钉死了多少儿童
how many children did the Great Masters nail to mileposts?
一百六十三人  卡丽熙
163, Khaleesi.
没错  就是这个数
Yes, that was it.
陛下  我有一言  可讲与否
Your Grace, may I have a word?
这是您的城市了
The city is yours.
这里所有人都是您的臣民
All these people, they're your subjects now.
有时用仁慈回应不公
Sometimes it is better to answer injustice
收效更好
with mercy.
我要用正义回应不公
I will answer injustice with justice.
这是搞什么
What the hell was that?
这是我用你自己的手
That was me knocking your ass to the dirt
打得你嘴啃泥
with your own hand.
你倒是天赋奇才
You're a rare talent.
最擅欺负残废
When you're fighting cripples, anyway.
你学的是乖娃娃打架
You learned to fight like a good little boy.
我敢打赌  你背后捅疯王那一剑
I'll bet that thrust through
招式也一定美如画
the Mad King's back was pretty as a picture.
你要打得漂亮还是要赢
You want to fight pretty or you want to win?
你跟我弟弟也这样讲话
You talk to my brother this way?
一直这样
All the time.
他早习惯了
He got used to it.
你说是他干的吗
Do you think he did it?
不是
No.
他自然恨那个小变态
Oh, he hated the little twat, sure.
可是谁不恨呢
But who didn't?
下毒也不是他的风格
And poison's not his style.
要说起来  谋杀也不是
Or murder, for that matter.
你想弄清楚  干吗不去问他
You want to know for sure, why don't you ask him?
你还没去看过他吧
You haven't been to see him yet, eh?
今天到此结束
We're done for today.
你弟弟给你说过我怎么开始为他效力的吗
Your brother ever tell you how I came into his service?
你在鹰巢城比武审判中做他的代理骑士
You stood for him in his trial by combat at the Eyrie.
对
Aye.
可是当艾林夫人要求当日比武审判
But only when Lady Arryn demanded the trial take place that day.
你才是他的首选
You were his first choice.
他指定你为代理骑士
He named you for his champion
因为他知道你会昼夜兼程赶去为他而战
because he knew you would ride day and night to come fight for him.
你现在会为他而战吗
You gonna fight for him now?
说句实话  这儿还不算太糟
To tell you the truth, this isn't so bad.
四面有墙  撒尿有壶
Four walls. A pot to piss in.
我被拴在根木桩上
I was chained to a wooden post
在自己的屎尿里泡了几个月
covered in my own shit for months.
你这是在宽慰我吗
Is that supposed to make me feel better?
有那么点意思吧
Maybe a bit.
抱歉没早些来
I'm sorry I didn't come sooner.
心情太复杂  是啊
It's complicated, yes.
-咱们老姐怎样了  -你说会怎样
- So how is our sister? - How do you think?
她儿子死在她怀里
Her son died in her arms.
她儿子
Her son?
别这样
Don't.
你知道接下来会怎样吗
You know what's coming?
对我的弑君罪进行审判  我知道
My trial for regicide. Yes, I know.
我知道七国上下都认定我有罪
I know the whole bloody country thinks I'm guilty.
我知道我的三位法官之一
I know that one of my three judges
早就无数次盼我死掉
has wished me dead more times than I can count.
而那位法官正是我父亲
And that judge is my father.
至于瑟曦
As for Cersei,
八成正想方设法省去审判
well, she's probably working on a way
直接找人弄死我
to avoid a trial altogether by having me killed.
既然你提起来  她的确要求过
Now that you mention it, she did ask.
那我是不是该闭上眼睛转过身去
So, should I turn around and close my eyes?
那要看
Depends.
是你做的吗
Did you do it?
弑君兄弟
The Kingslayer brothers.
你喜欢吗  我很喜欢
You like it? I like it.
你当真在问我有没有杀你儿子
You're really asking if I killed your son?
你当真在问我会不会杀亲弟弟
Are you really asking if I'd kill my brother?
我怎么帮你
How can I help you?
你可以放我出去
Well, you could set me free.
你知道我不能
You know I can't.
那就没什么可说的啦
Then there's really nothing else to say.
你要我怎么做  杀掉守卫
What do you want me to do? Kill the guards?
把你塞进马车偷偷带出城
Sneak you out of the city in the back of a cart?
我是御林铁卫队长
I'm the Lord Commander of the Kingsguard.
抱歉  我忘了
Sorry, I'd forgotten.
害你措置失宜就太糟糕了
I'd hate for you to do something inappropriate.
失宜
Inappropriate?
你被控弑君  放你是叛国
You're accused of killing the king. Freeing you is treason.
可我并没有弑君
Except I didn't do it.
所以才要进行审判
Which is why we're having a trial.
审判
A trial.
就算真凶到铁王座前自首
If the killer threw himself before the Iron Throne,
供认罪行
confessed to his crimes,
并且拿出铁证
and gave irrefutable evidence of his guilt,
瑟曦也不会在意
it wouldn't matter to Cersei.
我的头不插上枪尖  她不会罢休
She won't rest until my head's on a spike.
不止你的
Not just yours.
她宣称找到珊莎·史塔克的人皆可受封骑士
She's offering a knighthood to whomever finds Sansa Stark.
不可能是珊莎做的
Sansa couldn't have done this.
她比七国任何人都有动机
She had more reason than anyone in the Seven Kingdoms.
乔佛里死去当晚她就消失了
Do you think it's a coincidence she disappeared
你说这是巧合吗
the same night Joffrey died?
不是  但...
No, but...
珊莎不是杀人凶手
Sansa's not a killer.
至少现在还不是
Not yet, anyway.
你要带我去哪儿
Where are you taking me?
我要迎娶你莱莎姨妈
I'm getting married to your Aunt Lysa.
她在鹰巢城等我们
She's waiting for us at the Eyrie.
你在那里会很安全
You'll be safe there.
是你杀了乔佛里吗
Did you kill Joffrey?
是我杀了乔佛里吗
Did I kill Joffrey?
我几周前就在艾林谷了
I've been in the Vale for weeks.
我知道是你
I know it was you.
是谁帮我实施密谋呢
And who helped me with this conspiracy?
有个唐托斯爵士
Well, there was Ser Dontos.
你利用他带我出君临
You used him to get me out of King's Landing,
可你不会信任他去刺杀国王
but you would never trust him to kill the king.
-为何  -以你的才智  不会信任酒鬼
- Why not? - Because you're too smart to trust a drunk.
那或许是你丈夫呢
Then perhaps it was your husband.
不是他
No.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
我就是知道
I just do.
你说对了
You're right.
乔佛里的死与他毫无瓜葛
He wasn't involved in Joffrey's death.
可你却有份
But you were.
记得唐托斯给你的那条漂亮项链吗
Do you remember that lovely necklace Dontos gave you?
我猜你肯定没发现  宴会过后
I don't suppose you noticed that a stone was missing
上面少了一颗宝石
after the feast.
那是毒药
The poison.
我不明白
I don't understand.
兰尼斯特给你钱财  权势
The Lannisters gave you wealth, power.
乔佛里封你为赫伦堡伯爵
Joffrey made you the Lord of Harrenhal.
没有动机  就没人会怀疑
A man with no motive is a man no one suspects.
永远令你的敌人迷惑
Always keep your foes confused.
他们搞不清你是何人所求何事
If they don't know who you are or what you want,
就不会知道你下一步如何打算
they can't know what you plan to do next.
我不相信
I don't believe you.
如果被他们发现  你的头会被插上枪尖
If they catch you, they'll put your head on a spike
就像我父亲一样
just like my father's.
你冒这么大的风险只为迷惑他们
You'd risk that just to confuse them?
太多人不敢冒险
So many men, they risk so little.
一辈子都在设法避免危险
They spend their lives avoiding danger.
他们都死了
And then they die.
为了我想得到的  我敢赌上一切
I'd risk everything to get what I want.
你想得到什么
And what do you want?
一切
Everything.
与兰尼斯特的友谊  的确令我收益颇丰
My friendship with the Lannisters was productive.
可乔佛里
But Joffrey,
一个头戴王冠的恶毒男孩
a vicious boy with a crown on his head,
不是可靠的盟友
is not a reliable ally.
谁能信任这样的朋友
And who could trust a friend like that?
谁会信任你呢
Who could trust you?
我不想要自己这样的朋友
I don't want friends like me.
我的新朋友会按理出牌
My new friends are predictable.
都是通情达理之人
Very reasonable people.
乔佛里的下场
As for what happened to Joffrey,
正是我的新朋友急切盼望的
well, that was something my new friends wanted very badly.
周到的见面礼
Nothing like a thoughtful gift
最能增进友情
to make a new friendship grow strong.
您这就要离开了
I can't believe you're going.
留我独自和这些人周旋
Leaving me alone here with these people.
也是时候了  孩子
The time has come, my dear.
没有什么比审判更乏味了
There's nothing more tedious than a trial.
除了这些花园
Except perhaps these gardens.
再跟这破园子里溜达下去
If I have to take one more leisurely stroll
我就要飞身跳崖了
through these gardens, I'll fling myself from the cliffs.
你去见过托曼吗
Have you been to see Tommen yet?
没有
No.
他们到底同意婚事了吗
Have they even agreed to the match?
也没人告诉我
No one tells me anything.
最初要嫁给你祖父罗斯的人并不是我
I wasn't originally meant to marry your grandfather Luthor, you know.
他本已和我姊妹
He was engaged to my sister,
你姨祖母维奥拉订婚
your great-aunt Viola.
而我要被许给某个坦格利安
I was to be given to some Targaryen or other.
那时候嫁进坦格利安家简直风光无限
Marrying a Targaryen was all the rage back then.
但当我看到未婚夫
But the moment I saw my intended,
那神经兮兮  獐头鼠目的模样
with his twitchy little ferret's face
和滑稽透顶的银发
and ludicrous silver hair,
我就知道这人不中用
I knew he wouldn't do.
所以在罗斯
So the evening
向我姊妹求婚的前夜
before Luthor was to propose to my sister,
我上完刺绣课回去时迷了路
I got lost on my way back from my embroidery lesson
误入了罗斯的寝殿
and happened upon his chamber.
瞧我多糊涂呀
How absentminded of me.
翌日一早  罗斯没有下楼求婚
The following morning, Luthor never made it down the stairs
因为那小子已经走不动路了
to propose to my sister 'cause the boy couldn't bloody walk.
等他能走了  心心念念的
And once he could, the only thing he wanted
还是我给他的一夜销魂
was what I'd given him the night before.
我厉害着呢
I was good.
我那是相当厉害
I was very, very good.
而你更厉害
You are even better.
但你要快快出手
But you need to act quickly.
瑟曦心肠狠毒  却并不傻
Cersei may be vicious, but she's not stupid.
她会抓紧时机挑拨那孩子对付你
She'll turn the boy against you as soon as she can.
等到大婚之日  一切就晚了
And by the time you're married, it'll be too late.
幸运的是  摄政太后
Luckily for you, the Queen Regent
此刻无暇分神对付你
is rather distracted at the moment.
她正忙着悼念亡子
mourning her dear departed boy,
指控自己亲弟弟是凶手
accusing her brother of his murder,
人家可是清白的
which he didn't commit.
可能是他干的呢
Well, he could have done.
他能  但不是他干的
He could have done, but he didn't.
-祖母  这谁知道呢  -我知道
- You don't know, Grandmother. - But I do know.
你不会真以为我会让你嫁给那个畜生吧
You don't think I'd let you marry that beast, do you?
什么  我不明白
What? I don't understand.
这件事你就不必放在心上了
Shh. Don't you worry yourself about all that.
做你该做的事就好
You just do what needs to be done.
使劲打
Bring it through!
再来
And again.
很好  不错
Very nice. Good.
很多野人都是双手持武器作战
A lot of wildlings fight with a weapon in each hand.
首要之事就是
First thing you want to do
打掉他们的武器  扭转劣势
is disarm them to try and even the odds.
看看大家都什么水平
Let's see what you can do.
奥利  你先观战
Olly, you just watch for now.
我也能打
I can fight.
你摸过剑吗
Have you ever held a sword before?
我是村里最厉害的弓箭手
I was the best archer in our hamlet.
我说真的
I was!
我相信你
I believe you.
以后出去猎兔子一定带你
We'll go hunting for rabbits one day.
现在你要好好看  好好学
Right now, watch and learn.
你们俩
You two.
慢慢来  试着打掉对方的武器
Take it slow, try and disarm each other.
你很会打
You know how to fight.
但何必下这么重手
You could have gone easier on him.
不下重手他就学不会
He wouldn't have learned anything that way.
雪诺大人
Lord Snow.
你这是干什么
What do you think you're doing?
葛兰和我在帮大家训练
Grenn and I were helping them.
葛兰是游骑兵  你是事务官
Grenn's a ranger. You're a steward.
你和那野贱人鬼混时忘了自己的身份吧
Maybe you forgot that while you were off with your wildling bitch,
我可没忘
but I didn't.
必须有人练兵
Someone has to train them.
反正轮不到你
And that someone isn't you.
去把夜壶倒了
Go find a chamber pot to empty.
快  去啊
Go on. Do it.
叛徒的野种
You traitor's bastard.
别给我抓住把柄
Give me an excuse.
现在可没有莫尔蒙护着你
Mormont's not here to protect you now.
都回去干活
Get back to work.
快
Now!
没听见吗  快
I said now!
那小子很得人心  你不行
The bastard's well-liked. You're not.
管他得不得人心  现在是打仗的时候
You think I care if they like me? We're at war.
只是暂时
For now.
但你不能一直代理总司令
But you can't be acting commander forever.
势必要举行选举
There will be a choosing.
那老学士肯定会坚持这样做
The old maester will insist on it.
你还是考虑一下
You might reconsider
他要攻打卡斯特堡垒的要求
his request to march on Craster's.
让叛徒们把雪诺解决掉
Let the mutineers take care of Snow.
不然你下半辈子恐怕要听他发号施令了
Or you might be taking orders from him the rest of your life.
你是私生子
A bastard, eh?
还以为你是贵族少爷
Took you for highborn.
我父亲是贵族
My father was highborn.
母亲不是
My mother wasn't.
在下洛克
Name's Locke.
琼恩·雪诺
Jon Snow.
你身手不错
You fight well.
因为什么到这儿来
What brought you up here?
责任感
A sense of duty.
我想为保卫王国贡献一份力量
I wanted to do my part for the safety of the realm.
我本是风暴之地的猎场督员
I was a game warden in the Stormlands.
给饥肠辘辘的孩子们喂了只稀罕的松鸡
Fed a prized partridge to my hungry kids.
结果因为太蠢  被抓了
I was stupid enough to get caught.
不想丢一只手  于是来了长城
Chose the Wall over losing my hand.
想着来这儿不用讨好该死的贵族老爷
Figured I wouldn't have to suck up to any highborn cunts here.
快点  动起来
Come on, get on with it.
你们等什么呢  等夏天来吗
What are you waiting for? Summer?
看来我错了
Guess I was wrong.
您找我  太后陛下
You sent for me, Your Grace?
太后陛下
Your Grace.
你还真是一本正经
How formal of you.
托曼门外安排了几个御林铁卫
How many Kingsguards are posted outside Tommen's door?
柏洛斯爵士今夜当值
Ser Boros is on duty tonight.
-明天是...  -就一个
- Tomorrow I believe-- - So one?
你只派一个人保护未来的国王
You have one man guarding the future king?
我保证托曼平安无事
I promise you Tommen's safe.
我们在保护他
We're protecting him.
就像你保护乔佛里一样吗
The way you protected Joffrey?
凯特琳·史塔克为什么放了你
Why did Catelyn Stark set you free?
-什么  -自从那头大母牛把你送回君临
- What? - I've been wondering for months.
我琢磨了几个月都没明白
Ever since that great cow brought you back to the capital.
她为什么放了你
Why did she set you free?
你知道原因
You know why.
她希望我把她的女儿们送回去
She'd hoped I'd send her daughters back to her.
是她希望  还是你许诺
She hoped or did you promise?
我向诸神发过誓
I swore by all the gods
只要她的女儿们还活着  就送回她身边
that if her daughters were alive, I'd return them to her.
这么说你向敌人发下了神圣的誓言
So you made a sacred vow to the enemy.
我想回到你身边
I wanted to get back to you.
莫非我该叫她滚开吗
Should I have told her to fuck off?
也就是说  你并非出自真心
You didn't mean it, then?
你对凯特琳·史塔克发的誓毫无诚意
You have no loyalty to Catelyn Stark?
凯特琳·史塔克死了
Catelyn Stark's dead.
如果我要你立即离开君临  找到珊莎
So if I told you to leave the capital right now and find Sansa,
如果我要你揪出那个凶残狠毒的小婊子
if I told you to find that murderous little bitch
把她的脑袋带回来
and bring me her head,
你会去做吗
would you do it?
我知道你见了提利昂
I know you went to see Tyrion.
那个谋害我们儿子的畜生
That creature who murdered our son.
我必须见他
I had to see him.
我必须亲口问他
I had to know for myself.
然后呢
And?
不是他干的  瑟曦
He didn't do it, Cersei.
你总是同情他
You've always pitied him.
我们可怜的小弟弟
Our poor little brother.
全世界都对不住他
Abused by the world.
亲生父亲和姐姐都瞧不起他
Despised by his father and sister.
如果可以  他会把我们全杀了
He'd kill us all if he could.
我要你派四个人日夜守在托曼门外
I want four men at Tommen's door day and night.
你可以退下了  队长
That will be all, Lord Commander.
突击爵士
Ser Pounce?
你是怎么通过御林铁卫那一关的
How did you get past the Kingsguard?
御林铁卫
Kingsguard.
我觉得你不该来这儿
I don't think you're supposed to be here.
母亲不准我夜间会客
Mother doesn't allow me to have visitors at night.
我不是客人  陛下
I'm not a visitor, Your Grace.
据说我会成为您的新娘
Word has it I'm to be your bride.
您知道包办婚姻的男女
Did you know that people in arranged marriages
通常要到婚礼当天才初次见面吧
often never meet until their wedding day?
在我们决定相伴一生之前
Before we decide to spend our lives together,
我们应该先了解对方
we ought to get to know one another.
您不这么觉得吗
Don't you think?
没错
Yes.
-但如果母亲发现了  -这是我们俩的秘密
- But if my mother found out-- - It can be our secret. Hmm?
既然我们要结为夫妻
If we're going to be man and wife,
我希望我们能有些秘密不让她知道
we'll have a few secrets from her, I hope.
那么  陛下
So, Your Grace...
怎么
Yes?
告诉我一个秘密
Tell me a secret.
你好啊  这位小朋友真漂亮
Hello. Aren't you a proper fellow?
这是突击爵士
That's Ser Pounce.
真是漂亮极了
Very handsome.
乔佛里不喜欢它
Joffrey didn't like him.
他威胁说要活剥了它
He threatened to skin him alive
把内脏混到我的食物里
and mix his innards up in my food
让我毫不知情地吃下去
so I wouldn't know I was eating him.
真残忍
That's very cruel.
我觉得您不是残忍的人
You don't strike me as cruel.
不是
No.
我想我不是
I don't think I am.
那我就放心了
That's a relief.
您知道我们结婚后会怎样吗
Because you know what happens when we marry?
我们在总主教面前起誓
We say our vows in front of the High Septon.
仪式结束后  还有宴会
And after the ceremony, there's a feast.
成婚之后  我就是您的了
When we marry, I become yours.
一生一世
Forever.
不早了
It's getting late.
我该走了
I should go.
我能再来看您吗
May I come and visit you again?
太好了
All right, then.
记住
Remember,
这是我们的小秘密
our little secret.
"詹姆·兰尼斯特爵士
"Ser Jaime Lannister.
十六岁被册封为骑士  并被任命为御林铁卫
Knighted and named to the Kingsguard in his 16th year.
君临城陷时
At the sack of King's Landing,
杀害国王伊里斯二世
murdered his king Aerys II.
后被劳勃·拜拉席恩赦免
Pardoned by Robert Baratheon.
由此得名弑君者"
Thereafter known as the Kingslayer."
书写白典是铁卫队长的责任
It's the duty of the Lord Commander to fill those pages.
我的篇章尚未写完
And there's still room left on mine.
瓦雷利亚钢剑
Valyrian steel.
是你的了
It's yours.
我不能接受
I can't accept this.
它是用奈德·史塔克的剑重铸的
It was reforged from Ned Stark's sword.
你要用它保护奈德·史塔克的女儿
You'll use it to defend Ned Stark's daughter.
你立过誓  将史塔克家的女儿带回母亲身边
You swore an oath to return the Stark girls to their mother.
史塔克夫人已死
Lady Stark's dead.
艾莉亚八成也死了
Arya's probably dead, too,
但仍有一线希望
but there's still a chance
找到珊莎  把她带到安全的地方
to find Sansa and get her somewhere safe.
还有一样东西要给你
I've got something else for you.
但愿没估错你的身板
I hope I got your measurements right.
我一定会找到她
I'll find her.
为凯特琳夫人
For Lady Catelyn.
也为你
And for you.
差点忘了
I almost forgot.
还有个礼物呢
I have one more gift.
我不需要侍从
I don't need a squire.
怎么不需要
Of course you do.
他会拖累我的
He'll slow me down.
我弟弟欠他一个人情  他在这里不安全
My brother owes him a debt. He's not safe here.
你这是保护他  此乃骑士风范
You're keeping him from harm. It's chivalry.
我不会拖累您的  爵士
I won't slow you down, ser--
小姐
my lady.
我保证侍奉好您
I promise I'll serve you well.
瞧  多好的小伙儿  你们相处得来
See? He's a good lad. You'll get along.
提利昂大人聊表心意
Compliments of Lord Tyrion.
他在黑水河一战用的斧子
His axe from the Blackwater.
还等什么呢  要吻别吗
What are you waiting for, a kiss?
还不去为小姐备马
Ready the lady's horse.
人们说好剑要配好名
They say the best swords have names.
想取什么名
Any ideas?
守誓剑
Oathkeeper.
再会  布蕾妮
Good-bye, Brienne.
快点  驾
Come on, move.
我就不应该把她送走
I should never have taken her away.
-她在这儿不安全  -她在那儿也不安全
- She wasn't safe here. - She's not safe out there.
我早该想到
I should have known.
你说了长城以南有野人
You told us there were wildlings south of the Wall.
如果他们正沿路掠夺村庄
If they're raiding the smaller villages,
鼹鼠村很快就会遭殃
Mole's Town could be next.
-黑城堡也无法幸免  -我得回去找吉莉
- Castle Black could be next. - I should go back for Gilly.
我们有令在身  任何人不得离开城堡
We have orders. No one's to leave the castle.
可是你就违过令  往南边去找罗柏
I remember when you disobeyed orders and rode south to help Robb.
我还记得追上我  把我带回家的人是谁
And I remember who came after me and brought me home.
我理解你的心情  相信我  山姆
I know how hard it is, Sam, believe me.
当你跟我说布兰往长城外去了
When you told me about Bran going beyond the Wall,
我满脑子想的都是
all I could think about was
赶紧恢复体力  好去找他
getting my strength back so I could go and find him.
我真希望当时能说服他跟我回来
I wish I could have convinced him to come back with me.
我尽力了  真的
I tried. Really, I did.
他们行进的速度能有多快
How fast could they travel?
一个弱智大块头用雪橇拉一个瘸腿的孩子
A crippled boy being pulled on a sledge by a simpleton?
不知道
I don't know.
可能已经走过几座野人村子了
They'd pass wildling villages.
他们应该能找到藏身的地方
They could try to find shelter at one of them.
野人都已经加入了曼斯的大军
The wildlings have joined up with Mance.
所有的村庄都不会有人住
Every village or sheltered place will be deserted.
除了...
Except...
卡斯特堡垒
Craster's?
你觉得布兰有可能找到...
You think Bran might have found--
雪诺
Snow.
我无意打扰二位
I don't mean to interrupt.
索恩要见你
Thorne wants to see you.
关于攻打卡斯特堡垒的提议
Your foray to Craster's Keep,
我打算批准
I'll sanction it.
但我不会派人为你助阵
But I won't order anyone to go with you.
全凭个人意愿
Volunteers only.
谢谢  艾里沙爵士
Thank you, Ser Alliser.
兄弟们
Brothers.
我将去长城外攻打卡斯特堡垒
I'm going beyond the Wall to Craster's Keep.
我要逮捕窝藏的叛徒  或者就地解决他们
I'm going to capture the mutineers holed up there or kill them.
在此  我呼吁诸位自愿与我同行
I'm asking for volunteers to come with me.
卡斯特堡垒距此处六十里路之遥
There's 60 miles of wilderness between here and Craster's
加之曼斯·雷德的大军已向我们逼近
and Mance Rayder has an army bearing down on us,
但我们别无选择
but we have to do this.
我们要想活命
Our survival may depend on
就必须先曼斯一步拿下叛徒
us getting to these mutineers before Mance does.
他们对长城了如指掌  深知我们的防御力
They know the Wall. They know our defenses.
而一旦曼斯也知道了  我们就回天乏术了
If Mance learns what they know, we're lost.
如果这还不足以让你们动容
But if that's not enough,
那么不妨想一想
then consider this.
如果我们守夜人是真兄弟
If the Night's Watch are truly brothers,
那么莫尔蒙总司令就是我们的父亲
then Lord Commander Mormont was our father.
他为了守夜人  鞠躬尽瘁死而后已
He lived and died for the Watch
却遭到自家人的背叛
and he was betrayed by his own men.
被那帮孬种从背后捅死
Stabbed in the back by cowards.
他不该落此下场
He deserved far better.
我们现在能做的  唯有还他公道
All we can give him now is justice.
谁愿与我同行
Who will join me?
我不能让新兵前往长城以北
I can't let a recruit come north of the Wall.
那让我宣誓即可
Then let me say my vows.
如果你要打仗  就得用会打的人
If it's a fight you're heading for, then you need men who know how.
谢了  兄弟们
Thank you, brothers.
不  不要
No, don't.
求你了  不要
Don't, please.
求求你  不要
Please don't. Ow!
你弄疼我了
You're hurting me.
来自琴酒巷的卡尔·坦纳
Karl Tanner from Gin Alley
正用该死的杰奥·莫尔蒙的头骨喝酒
drinking wine from the skull of Jeor fucking Mormont.
有何指示  总司令大人
Any command for us, Lord Commander?
你说什么
What's that?
把她们操死为止
Fuck 'em till they're dead?
听见没有  伙计们
Did you hear that, boys?
把她们操死为止
Fuck 'em till they're dead.
雷斯特
Rast.
出去喂那个畜生
Go outside and feed the beast.
我们应该杀了那东西
We should kill that thing.
你的臭洞子应该闭好才是
You should shut your fucking hole,
恶心的小贱逼
ugly little cunt.
长这么一副蠢蛋样儿
You look like a fucking ballsack.
丑死了  瞧瞧你这张蠢逼贱货脸
Ugly. Look at your stupid cunt face.
老子瞎找条沟撒泡尿  能淹死五个你这样的
I could piss in any gutter and soak five of you.
知道君临那边请我杀人给多少钱吗
Know how much they paid me to kill a man in King's Landing?
七个银币
Seven silvers.
只要说个名字  那人就看不到第二天的太阳
They told me a man's name and that man never saw daylight again.
没有一个傻蛋逃得出我手心
None of them cocksuckers got away from me.
我从九岁起就没输过
Haven't lost a fight since I was nine.
没准该输了
Maybe it's time.
你觉得呢
What do you think, eh?
没准你能干翻我
Maybe you're the man.
说啊  娘们
Eh, cunt?
我一点儿机会都没有
I wouldn't stand a chance.
我们都不行
None of us would.
我在琴酒巷可是传奇人物
I was a fucking legend in Gin Alley.
传奇啊他妈的
A fucking legend!
无论哪个骑士  我随时随地干翻他
I would take any knight-- any knight, any time.
披甲戴盔的娘们  全他妈的懦夫
Fucking cunts in steel plate. Fucking cowards.
-献给神的礼物  -献给神的礼物
- A gift for the gods. - A gift for the gods.
献给神的礼物
A gift for the gods.
这他妈的是什么
What the fuck is that?
卡斯特的最后一个孩子  是男孩
Craster's last child. A boy.
我要拿他怎么办
What am I supposed to do with him?
卡斯特怎么处置
What did Craster do with 'em?
现在就宰了  免得养大了学老爹的样吗
Kill 'em before they could grow up and do the same to him?
好吧
All right.
少张嘴要吃要喝
Don't need another mouth to feed.
-给我  -他不杀男孩
- Hand him over. - He didn't kill them.
-他拿去献祭  -给谁
- He offered them. - To who?
给神
To the gods.
异鬼
The white walkers.
献给神的礼物  献给神的礼物
A gift for the gods. A gift for the gods.
闭嘴
Shut up!
那么
So...
既然他能这么干
if it worked for him...
那就满足异鬼的心愿
Let's give the walkers what they want.
雷斯特正好顺路
Rast is headed that way.
红眼杂种
Pink-eyed fuck.
渴吗
You thirsty?
操
Fuck!
阿多
Hodor.
你们听见了吗
Do you hear that?
是婴儿吗
Is that a baby?
来了
It's coming.
我要去看看
I'm going out there.
不  我们不要分开
No, we need to stay together.
我去了
I'm going.
-布兰  布兰  -阿多  阿多
- Bran. Bran. - Hodor. Hodor.
-阿多  -布兰  怎么了
- Hodor. - Bran, what happened?
夏天受伤了  掉进了他们的陷阱
Summer, he's hurt. They've caught him in a trap.
谁的陷阱
Who?
我没看见  他们抓了我哥哥的狼
I didn't see, but they have my brother's wolf.
他们抓了白灵
They have Ghost.
他们是守夜人
They're Night's Watch.
看
Look.
琼恩可能在这里
Jon might be here.
要是琼恩在  为何把狼关在笼子里
If Jon was here, why would they put his wolf in a cage?
他们也许以前是守夜人  但现在不是了
They might have been Night's Watch once, not anymore.
这里不安全  我们必须走
We're not safe here. We need to go.
不
No.
布兰  我们必须马上走
Bran, we need to go now.
不救出夏天  我不走
I'm not leaving without Summer.
你记得笼子在哪里吗
Can you remember where the cage was?
堡垒的东边
The east side of the keep.
如果我一时半会没回来  我们就到...
If I'm not back soon, we'll meet--
阿多
Hodor.
阿多  阿多
Hodor. Hodor.
阿多
Hodor.
我要是有你这个块头  我他妈就天下无敌了
If I was your size, I'd be king of the fucking world.
扶他起来
Help him up.
料子不错
This is nice.
好皮子
Fine leather.
你不是野人
You're no wildling.
有地位  贵族家的
Important. Highborn.
你是谁
Who are you?
在我老家那里
You see, where I come from,
我这种平头百姓扇你这种小少爷的耳光
a commoner like me slaps a little lord like you,
右手铁定保不住
I'd lose my right hand.
但我们离家好远哦  不是吗
But we're a long way from home, aren't we?
还有你们两个
And the two of you,
怪模怪样的  跑到长城北边
fancy-looking folks north of the Wall
钻林子
creeping through the woods.
有点古怪啊
Isn't that a bit odd?
我喜欢你的卷发
I like your curly hair.
我妈就有这样的卷发
My mom had curls like that.
漂亮的棕色卷发
Beautiful brown curls.
为什么带个残废小子跑这么远来
Why'd you drag a crippled boy all the way up here?
看来你们以前没遇到过这种情况
See you haven't played this game before.
贵族人质
A highborn hostage,
值钱
that's valuable.
不过另外三人
But three of them,
白吃白喝养不起
that's a lot of mouths to feed.
-他这是什么毛病  -过来
- What the fuck's wrong with him? - Come here.
别  求你了  让我去帮帮他
No, please. Please. Please, let me help him.
-你是谁  -求你了
- Who are you? - Please.
-你是谁  -我是布兰登·史塔克
- Who are you? - I'm Brandon Stark!
临冬城的布兰登·史塔克
I'm Brandon Stark of Winterfell.
是琼恩·雪诺的弟弟
It's Jon Snow's brother.
没事  有梅拉呢  有我呢
It's Meera. It's Meera. I'm right here.
我还以为又是无聊的一天呢
And I thought this was gonna be another boring day.